A Guide to the Papers of Clifford Dowdey 1723-1970
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Clifford Dowdey 1723-1970
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
3809-e
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was gifted to the university on 22 May 1970.
Contents List
- Manuscripts
  - Lee 1965, AMs (Box 1)
    17 pp.
  - The Seven Days 1964, TMs with autograph corrections (Box 1)
    425 pp.
  - Lee 1965, TMs with autograph corrections (Box 1)
    150 pp.
  - Lee 1965, TMs with autograph corrections (Box 1)
    16 pp. not continuous
  - The Virginia Dynasties 1969, TMs with autograph corrections (Box 1)
    426 pp.
  - Lee 1965, TMs with autograph corrections (Box 2)
    850 pp.
  - The Generation of the Golden Age 1970, TMs with autograph corrections (Box 3)
    316 pp.
  - The Golden Age 1970, TMs with autograph corrections (Box 3)
    337 pp.
  - The Golden Age 1970, TMs (xerox) (Box 3)
    48 pp.
  - "Proprietary in Virginia" n.d., TMs with autograph corrections (Box 3)
    6 pp.
  - "The Year of the Settlement" n.d., TMs with autograph corrections (Box 3)
    18 pp.
  - Where the Last Rose Lingers n.d., TMs with autograph corrections (Box 3)
    294 pp.
  - Where the Last Rose Lingers(?) n.d., TMs (carbon) (Box 4)
    34 pp. unnumbered
  - Where the Last Rose Lingers(incomplete) n.d., TMs with autograph corrections (Box 4)
    80 pp.
  - Where the Last Rose Lingers(nonconsecutive pages) n.d., TMs (carbon) (Box 4)
    55 pp.
  - Where the Last Rose Lingers(incomplete) n.d., TMs with autograph corrections (Box 4)
    85 pp.
  - Unidentified manuscript pages dealing with the Lees n.d., TMs with autograph corrections (Box 4)
    11 pp.
  - The Virginia Dynasties 1969, Galleys (author's duplicate) (Box 4)
    170 pp.
  - The Golden Age 1970, Galleys (author's duplicate) (Box 5)
    152 pp.
  - The Land They Fought For 1955, Page Proof (Box 5)
  - The Land They Fought For 1955 (Box 5)
- Letters
  - Edward Riley to Clifford Dowdey 1968 Jul 8, TLS (Box 6)
    2 pp.
  - Suzanne Neale to Clifford Dowdey 1969 Oct 6, TLS (Box 6)
    3 pp.
  - Jane Tyler to Clifford Dowdey 1969 Oct 27, TLS (Box 6)
    1 p.
  - Jane Tyler to Clifford Dowdey 1969 Nov 14, TLS (Box 6)
  - Mary [Rackliffe] to Clifford Dowdey 1969 Dec 15, TLS (Box 6)
  - Monroe Fabian to Clifford Dowdey 1969 Dec 8, TL (Box 6)
  - Mary Rackliffe to Clifford Dowdey 1969 Dec 23, TL (Box 6)
  - Mary Rackliffe to Clifford Dowdey 1969 Dec 23, TL (copy) (Box 6)
  - Monroe Fabian to Clifford Dowdey 1969 Dec 31 (Box 6)
- Photographs and Prints
  - Sir William Berkley(?) by Sir Peter Lely n.d., Photo (of portrait) (Box 6)
  - Robert (King) Carter n.d., Photo (of portrait) (Box 6)
  - Print of Colonial House n.d., photogravure (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous
  - Notes on Richard Bland n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    1 p. 12 items; from William & Mary Quarterly and The Origins of the American Revolution
  - re: Braton Parish Church n.d., Pamphlets (Box 6)
    1 4 pp., 1 1p.
  - re: William Byrd II and William Byrd III n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    1 p., 15 items
  - re: Byrd-Spot Feud of 1713-1720 n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    23 pp.
  - re: Landon Carter n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    1 p. 10 items
  - re: Carter Family Genealogy n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: Chapter 4 of The Golden Age(Robert Carter) n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    21 pp.
  - re: Henry and Archibald Cary n.d., Note (Box 6)
    1 item
  - re: Committee on Correspondence, 1759 n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: Christ's Church n.d., Pamphlet; Notes (Box 6)
    8 pp.; 2 pp.
  - re: John Custis n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: Robert Dinwiddie and (Ben) Scotland n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    5 pp.
  - re: Dinwiddie, Berkley, and Botetourt n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    6 1 p. items
  - re: 18th Century Dress n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - Background notes on Dry, Robert Carter, and Governor Gooch (1722-1732) n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    16 1 p. items
  - re: economic situation of the mid 1700's n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    9 1 p. items
  - re: Francis Fauquier n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: French and Indian War n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    7 1 p. items
  - re: William Fitzhugh n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    3 1 p. items
  - re: George III and influence of 1760's n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: William Gooch n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: land apportionment during Gov. Gooch's reign n.d., photocopy article (Box 6)
    8 pp.
  - re: Benjamin Harrison n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: William Henry Harrison n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: Patrick Henry w/photocopy of "The Stamp Act" from book Patrick Henry n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    15 1 p. items
  - re: coming of independence n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: philosophical and relilgious influences on Thomas Jefferson n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - outline on Thomas Jefferson n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    4 pp.
  - Jefferson-Randolph Genealogy n.d., Genealogy (Box 6)
  - quotations from Laslett n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: R.H. Lee and Thomas Lee n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    4 1 p. items
  - re: John, James, and Ambrose Madison n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: Andrew and James Monroe n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: Thomas Nelson n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: Ohio Co. and Loyal Co. n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    10 1 p. items
  - re: Randolph, Jefferson, and Marshall Families n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    19 1 p. items
  - re: John Robinson and (Edmund) Pendleton n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: social chronology and birth and death dates of 18th century figures n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: Virginia's reaction to Stamp Act n.d., Xerox notes (Box 6)
  - re: Charles Townshend n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: Dr. Thomas Walker n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: Robert Walpole n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - re: George Washington and George Mason n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - Notes on opening section of ( The Golden Age) n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    9 pp.
  - re: Proprietary in Virginia n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    13 1 p. items
  - re: Chapter II of The Golden Age n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    51 1 p. items
  - re: Possible illustration for The Golden Age n.d., Notes (Box 6)
  - Bibliography of books used for ( The Golden Age) n.d., Notes (Box 6)
    49 1 p. items
  - "The Acquisitive Society" n.d., photocopy article (Box 6)
  - "Richard Bland: The Whig in America" n.d., photocopy article (Box 6)
  - re: Governor Fauquier n.d., photocopy article (Box 6)
  - 2 pp. from King Carter, The Man n.d., photocopy (Box 6)
  - Chronology of pre-revolution events n.d., photocopy article (Box 6)
  - Edward M. Riley's "Business Success in 18th century Williamsburg" n.d., photocopy article (Box 6)
  - Potpourri of sonnets, epigrams, register of House of Burgesses, etc., from Earl Gregg Swam Library Collection of William and Mary n.d., photocopy articles (Box 6)
    5l
  - [?] to Micajah Perry 1723 March 25, photocopy of letter transcript (Box 6)
  - [?] to Solomon Low 1723 July 5, photocopy of letter transcript (Box 6)
  - [?] to Micajah Perry 1723 July 13 (Box 6)
  - [?] to Robert Alexander 1723 Sep 30, photocopy of letter transcript (Box 6)
  - [?] to Micajah Perry 1723 Dec 27, photocopy of letter transcript (Box 6)
  - Unused scrap paper like those used in rough draft of The Golden Age n.d., scrap paper (Box 6)